<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R-house</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on R-house</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>jalendrum@gmail.com (Jamie Lendrum)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>jalendrum@gmail.com (Jamie Lendrum)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes learning is not fun</title>
      <link>/post/2018-01-02-frustrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jalendrum@gmail.com (Jamie Lendrum)</author>
      <guid>/post/2018-01-02-frustrations/</guid>
      <description>Happy New Year!
I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the time between Christmas and New Year being more productive than I would usually be, trying things out in R, some (relatively) successfully, others&amp;hellip;not so much.
I thought it would be worth writing about how embarking on Data Science isn&amp;rsquo;t all plain sailing, and can at times be incredibly frustrating! You often see people who make everything seem so effortless and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get such a skewed perception of how things are going to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio &#43; Blogdown &#43; Github &#43; Netlify = A winning formula</title>
      <link>/post/2017-12-29-blog-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jalendrum@gmail.com (Jamie Lendrum)</author>
      <guid>/post/2017-12-29-blog-setup/</guid>
      <description>I thought it was worth posting about how I set up this blog as I had enormous trouble setting it up. I’d never done anything like this before and so some Google searching exposed me to many different technologies, but I had no clue what they did, which were best/easiest to work with and which combination I needed to use them in.
First off, big thanks go to John Muschelli and his YouTube video which got me up and running in no time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars: Galaxy of Heroes - who knew a mobile game could be so complicated?!</title>
      <link>/post/2017-12-29-swgoh-mods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jalendrum@gmail.com (Jamie Lendrum)</author>
      <guid>/post/2017-12-29-swgoh-mods/</guid>
      <description>How I started playingWhat are mods??Laying the groundworkReading in game dataCleaning it upLet the shenanigans begin!!Attempt 2: Brute force…The eventual resignation…How I started playingBack in 2015, during the boring period between Christmas and New Year, I decided to try out a Star Wars mobile game. Star Wars: Galaxy of Heroes is essentially a jazzed up version of Top Trumps where you collect characters, upgrade them, and use them to earn rewards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>/post/2017-12-28-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jalendrum@gmail.com (Jamie Lendrum)</author>
      <guid>/post/2017-12-28-welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! A brief introduction to me is on the About page - head over there now before reading on!
So I&amp;rsquo;ve been a Data Scientist for about 6 months now and already I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve been on quite a journey. Below is a summary of some of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing, some of the choices I&amp;rsquo;ve made, and where I want to go next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jalendrum@gmail.com (Jamie Lendrum)</author>
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, my name is Jamie Lendrum and welcome to my blog R-house!
I work as a Data Scientist for the UK Government and I&amp;rsquo;ve created this site to share my development and my personal projects using the R environment.
I graduated from the University of Portsmouth in 2001 with a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Mathematics, and spent the first 15 years of my career working as an Operational Analyst. This basically involves using a spectrum of analytical techniques ranging from complex simulation modelling to expert judgement (often simultaneously) in order to answer complex questions, usually focussed on how and where money should be spent.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>